Carla Sahagun

DMV area | 571-982-9406 | daniela.sahagun03@gmail.com Github | LinkedIn | Portfolio Website

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Dependable and detail-oriented software engineer experienced in JavaScript, Ruby, Ruby on Rails-based programming and a background in customer service. Possess strong skills in organization and communication. Comfortable with working in a fast-paced environment, cooperating with a team and delivering exceptional experiences. Known for a strong work ethic, professional demeanor and the ability to learn new technologies quickly.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SQL, Git, Invision Studio.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Business Cyber Shield - Github | Demo

Single page application showcasing cybersecurity services built for a Virginia based startup.

- Implemented EmailJs a third party service to allow customers send emails requesting for more information.
- Integrated a user friendly and responsive interface to allow users find information quickly.
- Prepared for deployment and launched the site on Godaddy.

Find a Personal Chef "Cheffed" - Github | Demo

Allows users to showcase their dishes for the public, and to be able to get requests from customers.

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side.
- Integrated a user friendly interface with Semantic UI and CSS3 to make the user experience intuitive.
- Added a Ruby on Rails API backend and a Reactjs frontend.

Professional Portfolio "Carla Sahagun" - Github | Demo

Fully responsive single page application showcasing experience, projects and skills.

- Created and designed wireframes on Invision Studio before Production.
- Utilized HTML, CSS, JavaScript and PHP to build a fully responsive web app.
- Prepared for deployment and launched the site on Godaddy.

EXPERIENCE

Eddie Merlot's
Ashburn, Virginia
Server
01/2020 - Present

- Offered advice for entree, wine pairing and dessert items.
- Promptly deliver dishes to ensure proper temperature upon consumption.
- Memorized and recalled daily and seasonal specials.
- Delivered exceptional service by greeting and serving customers in a timely, friendly manner.

21 Great American Bistro

Fairfax, Virginia 03/2018 - 2019

Server / Bartender

- Maintained detailed knowledge of menu items and ingredients to drive sales.
- Provided recommendations about food and wine, and introduced daily specials.
- Maintained impeccable customer service to ensure guest satisfaction and dining experience.
- Demonstrated the ability to multi-task at a fast pace environment while dealing with various situations/individuals.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Immersive Software Engineering Program Washington, D.C. 03/ 2020 - 06/2020